Women's Club Records UA059
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Women's Club Records
1934 -- 1984
1917 -- 2000
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Women's Club
UA059
2.14 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized in three series: Administrative and financial records; Program and activity records; and Unprocessed accessions.
Biographical / Historical
The Women's Club was founded in 1908. Organized by wives of the faculty, its purpose was to foster relationships among women in the Tufts community, and further the interests of the University. The club organized various social events and programs such as collecting donations for soldiers during World War I. They also provided scholarships to female students at Tufts. To raise money for the scholarship, the club hosted a Jumbo fair and auction that featured books, crafts, and other items for sale. In addition, the club hosted the International Students Host program with the Fletcher School of Law & Diplomacy. Incoming international students would stay with a host family and attend events welcoming them to Tufts. The club was officially dissolved in 1985, but former members continued working with the Fletcher Host program.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, financial records, membership lists, scrapbooks, materials relating to the international student hosting program, and program advertisements from the Women's Club. Documentation for the formation and closure of the club is also present in the form of initial bylaws, application for non-profit status, and votes regarding the closure of the club.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Faculty; Curriculum and Instruction -- Scholarships, Fellowships, Awards; Student life
- Administrative and Financial Records, 1920 -- 1989; 1937 -- 1984; UA059.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contain administrative and financial records from the Women's Club. Included are minutes of the Executive Committee, The Antiques Study Group, general club meetings, treasurer's reports, membership lists, by-laws, correspondence, and general information and the history of the club.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Activities of the Tufts Women's Club, 1969 -- 1984; UA059.001.001.00001 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Antiques Study Group, 1937 -- 1970; UA059.001.001.00002 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - [Financial Records and Membership Lists], 1960 -- 1985; UA059.001.001.00003 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Meetings of the Executive Board, 1963 -- 1970; UA059.001.001.00004 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - [Membership Lists and Treasurer's Reports], 1975 -- 1978; UA059.001.001.00005 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - (Tufts) Women's Club, General, 1934 -- 1989; UA059.001.001.00006 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Tufts University Women's Club, 1971 -- 1984; UA059.001.001.00007 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
    This folder contains the club's constitution and by laws, correspondence, membership lists, program flyers, and copies of the club newsletter.
  - Tufts Women's Club Information, 1970 -- 1983; UA059.001.001.00008 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
    This folder contains the club's constitution and by laws, membership lists from 1970 - 1983, and treasurer's reports from 1980 - 1981.
  - Women's Club, Antiques Study-Group, correspondence, 1956 -- 1970; UA059.001.001.00009 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, Antiques Study-Group, meetings and reports, 1940 -- 1953; UA059.001.001.00010 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, Antiques Study-Group Program, 1945 -- 1970; UA059.001.001.00011 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, By-laws, 1950 -- 1976; UA059.001.001.00012 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, History (1920s), 1920 -- 1929; UA059.001.001.00013 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, Notes for Tea Chairmen, 1932 -- 1972; UA059.001.001.00014 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, President's Report, 1953 -- 1967; UA059.001.001.00015 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, Steward Papers, 1971 -- 1985; UA059.001.001.00016 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, Treasurer, 1947 -- 1974; UA059.001.001.00017 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
- Program and Activities Records, 1917 -- 2000; 1937 -- 1984; UA059.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains records pertaining to the various activities and programs of the Women's Club. Included are membership lists, correspondence, program advertisements, and club newsletters.
  - Bateman's of Lexington [International Student Host Program], 1971 -- 2000; UA059.002.001.00018 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
    This folder contains materials relating to the International Student Host program held in conjunction with the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Label with the original folder title had fallen off. Meaning of "Bateman's of Lexington" unclear.
  - Women's Club, American Red Cross, 1917 -- 1946; UA059.002.001.00019 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club: Dramatics, Hullaballou, 1957; UA059.002.001.00020 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club: Dramatics: photos, programs, 1925 -- 1960; UA059.002.001.00021 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
  - Women's Club, Programs, 1917 -- 1968; UA059.002.001.00022 (Box UA059 Shared 1)
- Additional accessions, UA059.003
  - History and Financial Records, UA059-001 (Box data_value_missing_833cab89745396d60aad11e4a8dd8a43, Box 1)
    20 years from date of creation.